Elena Ortega Frontend Engineer



Senior Frontend Engineer with over 8 years of experience with a passion for creating engaging user experiences. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and various frontend frameworks. Strong problemsolving skills and a keen eye for design.

github.com/elenaorfelinkedin.com/in/elenaorfe

elenaorfe@gmail.com

EU citizen

WORK EXPERIENCE



Mobile Application for a Client in the Mobility sector

10.2021 - Present

Lead develope

Developed an iOS and Android application using React Native that successfully amassed over 1.5 million users and achieved top ranking as the 1st free iOS app and secured 4th position on Android in Sweden

 $React \ Native \cdot React JS \cdot Typescript \cdot Storybook \cdot Graph QL \cdot Parcel \cdot Jest \cdot Datadog \cdot Firebase \cdot Playwright \cdot Fastlane \cdot Gitlab \cdot Scrum \cdot Fnalish$

Web & Mobile Application for a Client in the Prevention of Hazards sector

02.2021 - 09.2021

Fullstack develope

Led the development of a hazard prevention web platform, integrated interactive floor plans, safety guidelines. Provided primary support during the culmination phase, maintaining React Native iOS and Android applications.

ReactJS · Typescript · HTML · Scss · React Native · Firebase · NodeJS · Github · Scrum · Trello · English

Web Application for a Client in the University sector

10.2020 - 01.2021

Frontend develope

Developed a hate speech detection dashboard to collect and analyze data from multiple social media platforms, incorporating intuitive graphical representations to illustrate hate speech trends and patterns.

 $Angular \cdot \mathsf{Typescript} \cdot \mathsf{HTML} \cdot \mathsf{Scss} \cdot \mathsf{Bootstrap} \cdot \mathsf{D3} \cdot \mathsf{Gitlab} \cdot \mathsf{Scrum} \cdot \mathsf{Jira} \cdot \mathsf{English}$

Web aplication for a Client in the IoT sector

09.2019 - 10.2020

Frontend develope

Led the migration from AngularJS to Angular and developed new features for a cloud-based measurement data monitoring system.

Angular JS · Angular · Typescript · HTML · Scss · Bootstrap · Responsive Design · Maps API · il8n · Karma · RESTful API · Webpack · Gitlab · Scrum · Jira · English

Web aplication for a Client in the IoT sector

06.2019 - 08.2019

Frontend developer

Led a project where I integrated customer-developed API endpoints into a visual map, facilitating the mapping of stores within shopping malls through a custom CMS.

 $Figma \cdot ReactJS \cdot HTML \cdot Sass \cdot Material \ UI \cdot Maps \ API \cdot i18n \cdot RESTful \ API \cdot Babel \cdot Webpack \cdot Jest \cdot Selenium \cdot Gitlab \cdot Scrum \cdot Trello \cdot English$

Web application for internal use

01.2019 - 05.2019

Frontend develope

Developed a user interface optimized for office needs, delivering tailored information, and integrated the application with various social media APIs.

Sketch · Marvel · ReactJS · HTML · Sass · Material UI · Bitbucket · Scrum · Trello · English



Web application for a Client in the Insurance sector

02.2018 - 12.2018

Frontend develope

Led the digital transformation initiative for one of the largest insurance groups in Austria, Central, and Eastern Europe, spearheading the definition, analysis, and implementation of software products.

AngularJS·EC6·HTML·Sass·Bootstrap·Responsive Design·Handlebars·RESTful API·Scrum·Jira·Github·English

Web application for a Client in the Bank sector

05.2017 - 01.2018

rontend develope

Engaged in the digital transformation of a significant financial group, involving analysis of customer requirements, enhancement of form-based workflows, task estimation, form modeling, and frontend development.

Javascript · jQuery · HTML · CSS · Bootstrap · Responsive Design · RESTful API · Scrum · Jira · Github · English

Web application for a Client in the Bank sector

05.2016 - 04.2017

Frontend develope

Developed a credit card portal, involving analysis of customer requirements and tasks estimation, followed by frontend development.

 $Angular JS \cdot \mathsf{HTML} \cdot \mathsf{Sass} \cdot \mathsf{Bootstrap} \cdot \mathsf{Responsive} \ \mathsf{Design} \cdot \mathsf{RESTful} \ \mathsf{API} \cdot \mathsf{Scrum} \cdot \mathsf{Jira} \cdot \mathsf{Github} \cdot \mathsf{English}$

R&D Projects

Frontend developer

06.2015 - 04.2016

Implemented new features and enhancements for company products within the R&D department, utilizing MV* architecture, integrating social networks into a multichannel platform, and incorporating a workflow engine into a Java application.

 $Angular JS \cdot HTML \cdot CSS \cdot Mocha \cdot Facebook \ API \cdot Twitter \ API \cdot Yammer \ API \cdot Java \cdot Oracle \ D \cdot Activiti \cdot Alfresco \cdot English \ API \cdot Twitter \ API \cdot Yammer \ API \cdot Java \cdot Oracle \ D \cdot Activiti \cdot Alfresco \cdot English \ API \cdot Twitter \ API \cdot Twitter \ API \cdot Twitter \ API \cdot Java \cdot Oracle \ D \cdot Activiti \cdot Alfresco \cdot English \ API \cdot Twitter \ API$

SIDE PROJECTS

Website for Personal Portfolio

https://www.elenaorfe.com

Created a portfolio website using Next.js with Tailwind CSS, integrated an OpenAl-powered chatbot for natural conversations, and deployed the project on Vercel.

 $\mbox{Next.js} \cdot \mbox{Typescript} \cdot \mbox{Tailwind} \cdot \mbox{Sass} \cdot \mbox{Vercel} \cdot \mbox{ally} \cdot \mbox{OpenAl APl} \\ \cdot \mbox{D3}$

Website for an architecture and interior design studio

07.2021 - Present

01.2024 - Present

https://www.doscestudio.com

Developed a website with a headless WordPress CMS, integrated with Next.js with Tailwind CSS, and deployment on Vercel.

 $\label{eq:Next_js} Next.js \cdot Typescript \cdot Tailwind \cdot GraphQL \cdot Wordpress \cdot Webhosting \cdot ally \cdot OpenAl \ API \cdot D3$

Website for an art curator

09.2020 - Present

https://www.marinariera.com

Developed a website with a headless WordPress CMS, integrated with Next.js with Tailwind CSS, and deployment on Vercel.

 $\label{eq:Next_solution} Next.js \cdot Typescript \cdot Tailwind \cdot GraphQL \cdot Wordpress \cdot Web \\ hosting \cdot ally \cdot OpenAl \ API \cdot D3$

Website for a scout association 01.2019 - Present

https://www.gs125.com

Developed a WordPress plugin for a website.

PHP · Wordpress · Bootstrap · Web hosting

TECHNICAL SKILLS -

Frontend · React Native · ReactJS · Typescript · Storybook · GraphQL · HTML · Angular · Angular JS · Maps API · il8n · RESTful API · Sass · Material UI · Javascript · Next.js · OpenAI API infrastructure · Parcel · Firebase · Fastlane · Vercel testing · Jest · Playwright tool · Datadog · il8n style · Scss · Bootstrap · D3 · Responsive Design · Sass · Material UI · CSS · Mocha · Tailwind runtime · NodeJS SkillType.Testing · Karma · Jest · Selenium SkillType.Infrastructure · Webpack accessibility · ally cms · Wordpress

EDUCATION

Master in IoT, Domotics and Smart Cities

Salamanca

Erasmus Program

Dresde

Bachelor Degree in Industrial

2010-

2016-

2017

Malaga

Spanish English

German

Engineering

